Guide to the Al Qassim Family Collection of photographs AD.MC.031
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Al Qassim Family Collection
1960-1980
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.031
143 Photographic Prints 143 digital surrogates of photographic prints
This collection of photos represents the personal photography of Mr. Abdulghafoor Alqasim from different areas of United Arab Emirates. The images date from both before and after the birth of UAE as a country in 1971 as well as Mr. Abdulghafoor's trips to other countries throughout the world. The collection reflects Mr. Abdulghafoor's interest in photography when he was a student in Dubai in the nineteen-sixties and extends decades into the era of digital photography. Akkasah has worked closely with Mr. Abdulghafoor to assure that his family's photographs are digitally preserved not only for the sake of posterity but also to serve as important cultural documents of the birth and rapid growth of the United Arab Emirates as a nation.
Graphics Digital surrogates only - physical objects not deposited
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Collection was digitized as it was recieved.
Biographical / Historical
.
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in February 2017.
Scope and Contents
This collection of photos represents the personal photography of Mr. Abdulghafoor Alqasim from different areas of United Arab Emirates. The images date from both before and after the birth of UAE as a country in 1971 as well as Mr. Abdulghafoor's trips to other countries throughout the world. The collection reflects Mr. Abdulghafoor's interest in photography when he was a student in Dubai in the nineteen-sixties and extends decades into the era of digital photography. Akkasah has worked closely with Mr. Abdulghafoor to assure that his family's photographs are digitally preserved not only for the sake of posterity but also to serve as important cultural documents of the birth and rapid growth of the United Arab Emirates as a nation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection obtained directly from Mr. Abdulghafoor Alqasim.
United Arab Emirates; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates
- Al Qassim Family Collection Prints (Object AD_MC_031_ref168)
  - A reception for Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum during the grand opening of the Dubai Airport with an Iran Air plane in the background. 5.2 x 7.2 cm, 1960 (Object AD_MC_031_ref1)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Events/Occasions; Regional/National Dress; Airports; Regional/National Dress; Airplanes; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - A boy holding a rifle in Ras al-Khaimah. 8.7 x 6.3 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref2)
    Deserts; Landscapes; Children; Individual Portraits; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Guns; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - An Iran Air plane at the old Dubai Airport. 6.2 x 8.8 cm, 1960 (Object AD_MC_031_ref3)
    Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Airports; Airplanes; Arabic Writing; Transportation; Group Portraits
  - Group trip to Ras al-Khaimah. 6.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref4)
    Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; Hats; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Men; Transportation
  - Group trip to Al Kharan, Ras al-Khaimah. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref5)
    Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Tents; Deserts; Men; Group Portraits; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A picnic trip in the desert. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref6)
    Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Cars/Trucks; Picnic; United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Hats; Smoking; Deserts; Transportation; Tobacco pipes; Group Portraits
  - Al-Maktoom Bridge in Dubai. 7.2 x 9.0 cm, 19 February 1964 (Object AD_MC_031_ref7)
    Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Seas; Landscapes; Bridges
  - A school classroom during a test. 6.6 x 8.5 cm, 18 May 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref9)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students; Boys; Group Portraits; Children; United Arab Emirates; Teachers
  - A portrait of a boy in front of his house in Deira, Dubai. 6.2 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref10)
    Photographic Prints; Houses; Individual Portraits; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Children; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Al-Fahidi Fort in Dubai. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref11)
    Forts/Castles; Architecture; Arabic Writing; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Deserts
  - Group trip to Kharran, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 8 March 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref12)
    Deserts; Men; Guns; Weapons; Landscapes; Smoking; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Cigarettes
  - Men at a rest area during their trip to Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.8 x 8.6 cm, 25 August 1964 (Object AD_MC_031_ref13)
    Hats; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits
  - Group portrait of men during their trip to Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.8 cm, 1968 (Object AD_MC_031_ref14)
    Landscapes; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Men; Group Portraits; Outdoors
  - Field trip to Kharan, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 25 August 1964 (Object AD_MC_031_ref15)
    Group Portraits; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Outdoors; Landscapes; Cars/Trucks; Boys; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Transportation; Children; Cars/Trucks
  - Field trip to Kharan, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 9.0 cm, 1968 (Object AD_MC_031_ref16)
    Carpets/Rugs; Lanterns/Lamps; Arabic Writing; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Outdoors; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Picnic
  - View of Dubai in the sixties from the minaret of a mosque. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref17)
    Landscapes; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Buildings
  - View of Dubai from the minaret of a mosque. 7.0 x 8.9 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref18)
  - Al Shaab School in Dubai. 6.3 x 8.5 cm, 16 May 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref19)
    Flags; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Students; Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Schools/Education; Transportation; Children
  - Khatt, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref20)
    Palm Trees; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Deserts; Outdoors; Landscapes
  - Al-Salehia, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref21)
    Landscapes; Arabic Writing; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Palm Trees; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Agriculture/Farms
  - Al-Salehia, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref22)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Outdoors; Palm Trees; Landscapes; Agriculture/Farms
  - The minaret of a mosque in Dubai. 8.7 x 6.4 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref23)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Mosques; Arabic Writing; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites
  - Khatt, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref24)
    Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Deserts; Palm Trees; Outdoors; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Landscapes; Houses; Architecture; Buildings
  - A building at Dubai Creek. 6.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref25)
    Architecture; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - Portrait of a young man on the Al-Maktoum Bridge. 6.8 x 9.0 cm, 19 February 1964 (Object AD_MC_031_ref26)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Motorcycles; Men; Arabic Writing; Bridges; Individual Portraits
  - Boy scouts in their school. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 18 May 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref27)
    Boys; Scouts; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; United Arab Emirates; Schools/Education; Arabic Writing; Children; Group Portraits
  - A fort on a mountain in Oman. 6.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref28)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Forts/Castles; Oman
  - Dubai High School. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref29)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Schools/Education; Buildings
  - Al-Fahidi Fort in Dubai. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref30)
    Architecture; Arabic Writing; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Forts/Castles
  - The Iranian School in Dubai. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref31)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Iran; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Schools/Education; Buildings
  - A tank for drinkable water from Al Awir in Dubai. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref32)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Drinks/Beverages; Water; Buildings; Arabic Writing
  - Preparation of the Eid sacrifice during an outing in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref33)
    Sheep; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Boys; Eid; Animals; Children; Group Portraits
  - Mountains in Masafi. 6.7 x 8.9 cm, 25 February 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref34)
    Mountains/Hills; United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Photographic Prints; Landscapes
  - Preparing food during a trip in Al Kharran in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref35)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Food; Men; Group Portraits
  - Rifle training in the desert. 6.1 x 9.0 cm, 19 November 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref36)
    Deserts; Guns; Boys; Weapons; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; United Arab Emirates; Landscapes; Children; Group Portraits
  - School trip to Masafi. 9.0 x 6.6 cm, 25 February 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref37)
    Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Gardens; Carpets/Rugs; Boys; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Children; Group Portraits
  - Al-Salehia, Ras Al-Khaimah. 8.7 x 6.4 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref38)
    Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Smoking; Men; Cars/Trucks; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Boys; Taxis; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Transportation; Cigarettes; Group Portraits
  - Students taking a test in a classroom in Dubai. 6.1 x 8.6 cm, 18 May 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref39)
    Teachers; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Boys; Students; Schools/Education; Children; Group Portraits
  - Irrigation system on a farm. 8.8 x 6.9 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref40)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Palm Trees; Water; Arabic Writing; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; United Arab Emirates; Irrigation; Agriculture/Farms
  - Boys swimming in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref41)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Boys; Swimming Pools; Arabic Writing; Children; Swimming; Group Portraits
  - Trip to Ras Al-Khaimah's mineral springs. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref42)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Cars/Trucks; Boys; Arabic Writing; Children; Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Men; Group Portraits
  - Entrance to a house in Dubai. 6.9 x 8.9 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref43)
    Doors/Entrances; Arabic Writing; Buildings; Houses; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Boys; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Bicycles/Tricycles; Children
  - Backyard garden in Dubai. 6.5 x 8.7 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref44)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Animals; Agriculture/Farms; Gardens; Photographic Prints
  - Goat in a house backyard in Dubai. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref45)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Animals; Houses; Goats; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings
  - A classroom. 6.2 x 8.6 cm, 18 May 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref46)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Students; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Children
  - A school's football field. 6.5 x 8.4 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref47)
    Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Schools/Education; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Students; Boys; Football; Sports; Children; Group Portraits
  - Highschool football field in Dubai. 6.5 x 8.6 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref48)
    Photographic Prints; Football; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Houses; Uniforms; Men; Schools/Education; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Sports; Children; Group Portraits
  - Students in classroom in Masafi Area, Dubai. 6.6 x 8.8 cm, 25 February 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref49)
    Students; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Men; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Furnishings; Schools/Education; Children; Teachers; Group Portraits
  - Portrait of Abd Alghafour on a desert trip. 6.6 x 8.6 cm, 8 April 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref50)
    Arabic Writing; United Arab Emirates; Deserts; Boys; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Outdoors; Individual Portraits
  - Group trip to the desert. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref51)
    Cars/Trucks; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; United Arab Emirates; Deserts; Transportation; Group Portraits
  - Portrait of Abd Alghafour Al-Qassim in Khatt, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 8.5 cm, Circa 1960-1969 (Object AD_MC_031_ref52)
    Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Lanterns/Lamps; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Men
  - The garden of the ruler of Ras Al-Khaimah Sheikh Saqer. 6.8 x 9.0 cm, 25 February 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref53)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Gardens; Men; Boys; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - School trip to Masafi, Dubai. 7.3 x 11.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref54)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Students; Schools/Education; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Men
  - Group trip to Al Batinah, Oman. 6.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref55)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Boys; Men; Outdoors; Oman; Children; Group Portraits; Cars/Trucks; Deserts; Transportation; Group Portraits; Landscapes
  - Group portrait in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 8 March 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref56)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Deserts; Men; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Clocks/Watches; Tea/Coffee; Group Portraits
  - A school in Dubai. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 18 May 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref57)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Students; Schools/Education; Palm Trees; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Children
  - Houses made from palm leaves (arish), Dubai. 9.0 x 6.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref58)
    Water; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palm Trees; Houses; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Boats/Ships; Buildings
  - The reception of Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai Airpot. 6.6 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref59)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Airports; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Cars/Trucks; Streets/Roads; Transportation
  - Landscape of Dubai. 6.9 x 9.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref60)
    Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Houses; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Landscapes; Forts/Castles
  - Landscape of Dubai with view of Khor Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref61)
    Houses; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Water; Boats/Ships; Landscapes
  - Landscape of Khor Dubai from a mosque in Bur Dubai. 8.6 x 14.0, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref62)
    Landscapes; Buildings; Water; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Landscape of Khor Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref63)
    Water; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Boats/Ships; Buildings
  - Landscape of Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref64)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Buildings; Architecture
  - Iranian School in Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref65)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Schools/Education; Buildings
  - Khor Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref66)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Houses; Boats/Ships; Water; Arabic Writing; Landscapes
  - The old Dubai Airport. 6.6 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref67)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Airports; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
  - A reception for Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai Airport. 5.5 x 7.3 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref68)
    Men; Airports; Regional/National Dress; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Sheikhs; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Royalty; Political Leadership; Officials; Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum, Sheikh, 1912-1990
  - A boat in Khor Dubai 6.2 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref69)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Boats/Ships; Men; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water
  - Water tank in Bur Dubai. 6.4 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref70)
    Water; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - Al Maktoum Bridge in Dubai. 7.1 x 9.0 cm, 19 Februrary 1964 (Object AD_MC_031_ref71)
    Boats/Ships; Water; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Bridges; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A reception of Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai Airport. 5.5 x 7.4 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref72)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Airplanes; Iran; Sheikhs; Airports; Men; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Royalty; Political Leadership; Officials; Transportation; Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum, Sheikh, 1912-1990
  - Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum in the Dubai Airport. 5.5 x 7.4 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref73)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Airports; Men; Arabic Writing; Sheikhs; Regional/National Dress; Crowds; Group Portraits; Royalty; Political Leadership; Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum, Sheikh, 1912-1990
  - A crowd welcoming Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai airport. 6.7 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref74)
    Arabic Writing; Sheikhs; Airports; Photographic Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Crowds; Group Portraits; Royalty; Political Leadership; Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum, Sheikh, 1912-1990
  - Entrance to Dubai airport's old building. 8.7 x 6.2 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref75)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Crowds; Flags; Airports; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Group Portraits; Doors/Entrances
  - Deira Clocktower. 6.3 x 8.9 cm, Circa 1965 - 1970 (Object AD_MC_031_ref76)
    Clocks/Watches; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Monuments/Memorials
  - School in Masafi, Dubai. 6.6 x 8.9 cm, 25 February 1965 (Object AD_MC_031_ref77)
    Arabic Writing; Schools/Education; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Teachers; Individual Portraits
  - View of Dubai from a mosque in Bur Dubai. 6.3 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref78)
    Palm Trees; Houses; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Landscapes
  - Boys in a school in Masafi, Dubai. 6.7 x 9.0 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref79)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Men; Schools/Education; Students; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Teachers
  - Al Fahidi Fort, Dubai. 6.5 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref80)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Forts/Castles
  - A man in front of Al Fahidi Fort, Dubai. 6.7 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref81)
    Forts/Castles; Men; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Dubai Airport's old building. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref82)
    Cars/Trucks; Airports; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Transportation; Buildings
  - Man in front of Dubai Airport's main entrance. 6.2 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref83)
    Airports; Men; Doors/Entrances; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - Dubai's old airport. 6.1 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref84)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Airports; Buildings
  - A building in Dubai. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref85)
    Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings
  - Customs point of Khor Dubai. 5.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref86)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Water
  - Khatt Fort, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.5 x 8.5 cm, 8 March 1962 (Object AD_MC_031_ref87)
    Mountains/Hills; Forts/Castles; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Landscape of houses by the ocean. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref88)
    Landscapes; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Beaches; Houses; Water; Buildings; Architecture
  - Dubai Landscape. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref89)
    Houses; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Buildings
  - View of houses in Bur Dubai. 6.2 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_031_ref90)